<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CEDIS</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on CEDIS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:50:20 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fields of Activity</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/lista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:37:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/lista/</guid><description>Software Development and Engineering; Development Methodologies and Approaches; Emerging Technologies and Innovation; Human and Managerial Aspects; Education and Learning; Research and Development in Software Products and Solutions. Learn more.</description></item><item><title>Learning Analytics and Educational Management</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/learning_analytics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 02:18:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/learning_analytics/</guid><description>An interdisciplinary area that combines data analysis, computer science, and educational psychology to enhance learning and educational environments. By collecting, analyzing, and interpreting data about learners and their contexts, it provides insights to personalize education, identify students who need more support, and improve educational outcomes.</description></item><item><title>Gamification</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/gamification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:37:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/gamification/</guid><description>Gamification is a process that uses elements, techniques, and game design mechanics in contexts not related to games, aiming to increase user motivation, participation, and engagement. Gamification has been applied in various fields, such as education, marketing, health, and corporate training.</description></item><item><title>High-Performance Computing and Cloud Computing</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/hpc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:37:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/hpc/</guid><description>High-Performance Computing and Cloud Computing is a dynamic and essential field in computer science, focused on the development and application of advanced computing systems capable of processing large amounts of data at extremely high speeds.</description></item><item><title>Canal Ciência Project</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/projects/canal_ciencia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 17:08:50 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/projects/canal_ciencia/</guid><description>A research project in partnership with IBICT and funded by FINATEC, aimed at enhancing the user experience of the Canal Ciência through the use of gamification.</description></item><item><title>Project DFCris</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/projects/dfcris/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 02:59:29 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/projects/dfcris/</guid><description>A research project in partnership with IBICT and funded by FAP/DF.</description></item><item><title>André Luiz Peron Martins Lanna</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/andre_lanna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:50:20 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/andre_lanna/</guid><description>Associate Professor at the University of Brasília (UnB), working in the undergraduate Software Engineering program and the Graduate Program in Applied Computing.</description></item><item><title>Sergio Antônio Andrade de Freitas</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/sergio_freitas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:49:57 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/sergio_freitas/</guid><description>Full Professor at the University of Brasília (UnB), working in the undergraduate Software Engineering program and the Graduate Program in Applied Computing.</description></item><item><title>Daniel Sundfeld Lima</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/daniel_lima/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:46:38 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/daniel_lima/</guid><description>Professor Adjunto da Universidade de Brasília (UnB), atuando no curso de graduação em Engenharia de Software.</description></item><item><title>Cristiane Soares Ramos</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/cristiane_ramos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:44:02 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/cristiane_ramos/</guid><description>Professor at the University of Brasília (UnB), working in the undergraduate Software Engineering program.</description></item><item><title>André Corrêa da Silva</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/andre_silva/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:50:20 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/people/andre_silva/</guid><description>Undergraduate in Software Engineering, University of Brasília</description></item><item><title>Our Partners</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/parceiros/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 23:13:19 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/parceiros/</guid><description>CEDIS benefits from the support and collaboration of various research partners, significantly contributing to the advancement of knowledge and innovation in their areas of operation. Among these partners, the following stand out:
A3M - Learning for the Third Millennium Program: An innovative program from the University of Brasília, aimed at integrating advanced technologies and methodologies in education, focusing on preparing for the challenges of the third millennium. More information can be accessed at A3M UnB.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/contact/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 03:10:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/contact/</guid><description>The Center for Studies, Development, and Innovation in Software (CEDIS) is located at the Gama Faculty (FGA) of the University of Brasília (UnB):
Address: Container 19,
Gama Faculty - FGA. University of Brasília - UnB.
Special Industry Area Projection A.
East Sector. Gama. ZIP Code: 72.444-240. Email: cedis@unb.br
https://youtube.com/@CedisUnB
A National Council for Scientific and Technological Development (CNPq) research group.</description></item></channel></rss>