<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CEDIS</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on CEDIS</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:05:19 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fields of Activity</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/lista/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:37:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/lista/</guid><description>Software Development and Engineering; Development Methodologies and Approaches; Emerging Technologies and Innovation; Human and Managerial Aspects; Education and Learning; Research and Development in Software Products and Solutions. Learn more.</description></item><item><title>Learning Analytics and Educational Management</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/learning_analytics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 02:18:30 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/learning_analytics/</guid><description>An interdisciplinary area that combines data analysis, computer science, and educational psychology to enhance learning and educational environments. By collecting, analyzing, and interpreting data about learners and their contexts, it provides insights to personalize education, identify students who need more support, and improve educational outcomes.</description></item><item><title>Gamification</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/gamifica%C3%A7%C3%A3o/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:37:18 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/areas/gamifica%C3%A7%C3%A3o/</guid><description>Gamification is a process that uses elements, techniques, and game design mechanics in contexts not related to games, aiming to increase user motivation, participation, and engagement. Gamification has been applied in various fields, such as education, marketing, health, and corporate training.</description></item><item><title>Sergio Antônio Andrade de Freitas</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/pessoas/sergio_freitas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:49:57 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/pessoas/sergio_freitas/</guid><description>Full Professor at the University of Brasília (UnB), working in the undergraduate Software Engineering program and the Graduate Program in Applied Computing.</description></item><item><title>Our Partners</title><link>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/parceiros/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 23:13:19 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://sergioaafreitas.github.io/en/parceiros/</guid><description>CEDIS benefits from the support and collaboration of various research partners, significantly contributing to the advancement of knowledge and innovation in their areas of operation. Among these partners, the following stand out:
A3M - Learning for the Third Millennium Program: An innovative program from the University of Brasília, aimed at integrating advanced technologies and methodologies in education, focusing on preparing for the challenges of the third millennium. More information can be accessed at A3M UnB.</description></item></channel></rss>